your aunt was not a Westerner Well, she had a
твоя ж тётка не западенка была Ну она же
normal attitude towards Russia Yes, they
нормально к России относилась Да они
used to have a normal attitude towards Russia So, what, what,
раньше нормально к России Так а что что
what happened What did they do to her that she
что случилось Что с ней сделали что она
started talking like that about you and Russia Well,
так начала говорить про тебя и Россию ну
here it all started and that's it Wait, what your
вот началось сво и всё так подожди то
aunt didn't
что тётка не
appreciate Do you want to free him,
оценила вы хотите освободить его
her Well, listen, for them Well, we are
её Ну слушайте для них же Ну мы
occupiers who attacked
оккупанты напали
Hello, hello What kind of flag is that in the back, it's
Привет здравствуйте Что за флаг сзади
interesting I just can't see it completely
интересный просто не вижу его полностью
Yes, why would I care if you hang it
Да зачем интересно раз ты вешаешь то
to
чтоб
show it No, it's just that I hang it so that it
показать Да нет просто ну вешаю для того
hangs in my house VD or the flag of
чтобы висел у меня дома ВД или флаг
some country I'm also interested Well, show me
какой-то страны тоже интересно ну покажи
VDV
ВДВ
Show me I remember
Покажи вижу
where it's
пом откуда
from Russia Yes, you can see it on the walls And what city is it And what can you
с России Да видно по стенам А город
see on the walls, the design is
какой А что по стенам видно дизайн
Russian Yes, I just haven't done the renovations yet
русский Да просто ремонт ещё не сделал
Well, everyone I talk to in Russia is
Ну вот все с кем общаюсь с россие у всех
either renovating something or everyone is at their dacha Not me, the
что-то ремонт идёт либо все на даче не я
secondary market Just what city are you from Rostov
вторичку просто какого города ты Ростов
the Great or on Dana on Dana I understand I
Великий или на Дану на Дану понял я и
come from Rostov the Great I was just so
родом из Ростова Великого Просто я так
surprised when you said Rostov and not
удивился когда ты сказал Ростов а не
Rostov on  Don,
Ростов на Дону
we just all say Rostov
на у нас просто все говорят Ростов
Well, we call it We are from Rostov, we
Ну мы называем Мы из Ростова мы ваш
always call your Rostov Rostov is given
Ростов называем всегда Ростов надано
completely I have been living in Britain for 18 years now,
полностью Я живу сейчас 18 лет в
in 2 years it will be the
Британии через 2 года уже будет
twentieth, you are communicating here Yes, I just
двадцатом общаешься тут Да просто первый
came in for the first time, in fact, you served since you are a
раз зашёл на самом деле ты служил раз ты
paratrooper Well, I am not a paratrooper, I am a
ВДВшник Ну я не ВДВшник я
paratrooper I understood And why didn’t you go to fight Why did you decide to
Десантник понял А что не пошёл воевать
fight
взяли воюешь
Well, yes, and why are you sitting at home on
Ну да а что ж дома сидишь в
vacation, it’s funny there are people there, mobile phones They have
отпуске прикольно там людей мобили Зро
n’t let them go anywhere for 3 years already And you on
их 3 года уже никуда не отпускают А ты в
vacation, what a joke I was
отпуск какой-то прикол Я
mobilized, they didn’t let me go home
мобилизованный мобико не отпускали домой
on vacation yet Well, this is this is complete
ещ на отпуска Ну это это это полный
Sorry for my
Извините за
mobilization, I was mobilized on the 2nd,
мобилизованный 2
I am on vacation for the third time already, and the
го я в отпуске уже третий раз а
fourth time I was on vacation, I was already wounded
четвёртый раз я в отпуске уже раненый
three times, how much
был три раза сколько за ранени
did they pay for the wounded, like everyone else Well, I don’t know
выплачивали как и всем Ну я не знаю
how much you have
сколько у вас
here, three, three, I heard that it was like
тут три три по Я слышал что вроде как
three, but in some cases they said
три но в некоторых говорили вариантах
that it was less
что меньше
Dava plus the governor’s
Дава плюс губернаторские
600 I have a classmate from that  Rostov
600 У меня одноклассник из того Ростова
was Sanya Prokhorov also mobile Zro ii in the
был Саня Прохоров тоже мобили Зро ий в
twenty-second year in short he spent six months
двадцать втором году короче он полгода
In the war
пробыл На войне погиб
he died well in short here it turned out like they didn’t
он ну короче тут получилось ему типа не
give him payments for death because he well in short
выдали выплаты за смерть бо он ну короче
how his turret was blown off there he ran
как его башню там сорвало он побежал
like from his positions to be captured by the
типа со своих позиций в плен сдаться к
Ukrainians Yeah So he blew up on his
украинцам Угу Вот и подорвался на свои
mini which theirs were alive they put up theirs
мини которые свои живы выставили свои
put up mines from the Ukrainians here and he
выставили мины от украинцев вот а он
ran Like to surrender he
бежал Типа чтоб сдаться в плен бежал
ran Run ran stepped in short he has a
Бежал бежал наступил Короче у него там
video there Well they gave his mom a video
видео есть Ну мамке его передали видео
so that she would understand that like why there are no
чтобы она понимала что типа почему нету
payments she showed threw off
выплат она показывала скидывала потому
because we had been friends with him since childhood In
что мы с ним дружили с детства Вот у
short he has I don’t know what
него короче я не знаю что это за мина
kind of mine it is I don’t understand these mines but
такая я в этих не разбираюсь мина но у
in short he has an
него короче
under-ice mine maybe something from it can
подлёдная может что от неё тело
throw the body 10 m maybe
подкинуть на 10 м может
well exactly the full body whole no
ну именно полное тело цельное нет вот
sorry I didn’t mean it it was scary Well it just
сори я не хотел это страшно Ну просто
looked funny In short he has a leg
выглядело смешно Короче у него ээ нога
uh to one side
э в одну сторону
and a body with the second leg I  I didn't see the head
а туловища с второй ногой Я голову не
because it was spinning so
видел потому что оно так крутилось типа
fast, most likely the head was with this
быстро скорее всего голова была с этим с
body Yes, one leg flew off very
туловищем Да одна нога отлетела очень
quickly, so under a trajectory somewhere like this At
быстро так под траектории где-то вот Под
such an angle and went somewhere into the distance, you can't
таким углом и ушла куда-то вдаль там не
see where it fell, namely the body
видно куда она упала а именно то тело
that was naked, it flew up like this
которое с нагой оно вот так вверх
and fell there, in short, listen Well,
подлетела и ту упало короче слушайте Ну
maybe it was anti-tank, maybe they
может быть противотанковое может быть
just laid down the topic, different options
темку просто заложили разные варианты
can actually be just like that, damn,
могут быть на самом деле просто так блин
he
он
was at all, I wouldn't say that he was a military man,
вообще был я бы не сказал что он военный
yes, he served here, but
такой да он тут служил
in life he was a teacher at the
но так он в жизни был преподавателем в
university Well, I wasn't a military man either, I
университете Ну я тоже не был военным я
served and studied, and such an absurd
отслужил и учился да и такая нелепая
death, that is, he
смерть то есть
literally ran another
там уже буквально пробежал ещё метров
300-400 meters and would have surrendered normally, he would have been
300 400 и сдался бы нормально был бы
alive, but so, well, he stepped on his own
живой а так ну на свою же
mine,
мину
in short, damn, well, it turns out that he was buried
вступил короче блин ну и получается его
without that Well, how could he be buried without this
хоронили без вот той Ну как без этой
second leg and in a closed coffin, we didn't
ноги второй и в закрытом гробу мы его не
see him So, well, I didn't come Yes,
видели Так ну я не приезжал Да его
like his mother just sent off photos
типа мама просто фотографии скидывала
that the coffin was closed and wrote, yes, that in
что гроб закрытый был и писала да что в
coffin like Legs this one is not there he himself is
гробу типа Ноги этой нет сам он
very badly disfigured because there
изуродовано очень сильно потому что там
well Dad I was talking to his dad because
ну Батя я с батей его говорил потому что
mom just sent the photos she was crying a lot
мамка так только фотки скинула она очень
and Bat is burning
ревела а Бат гори
Bat this character is a
Бат сиго характера
press by birth like well Russian but from the
жим за родом типа ну русский но с
Caucasus from Stavropol somewhere a Cossack or
Кавказа со Ставрополья где-то казак или
whoever he said that damn I have
кто он то говорил что блин я ещё такого
never been such a mince with a person his dad
фарша с человеком не был его батя в
was in the Chechen company Yes all sorts too I have
Чеченской был компании Да всякое тоже
seen but he says I have never seen anything
Видал но говорит я вот такого не видел
like well just to come here for Listen here
типа ну прям чтоб сюда вот за Слушай вот
what do you think for what my
как ты считаешь за что погиб Мой
classmate died yes I can't say for what
одноклассник да я не могу сказать за что
he
он
died just
погиб просто
there in Ukraine I watched Here is this story
там в Украине Я смотрел Вот этот сюжет
they filmed from this with a quadcopter here
они с этого с квадрокоптера сняли вот э
there is
там есть
such a military man he is a military man and blogger Marcus
такой военный он военный и блогер Маркус
in Ukraine I watch him he posted Here is
в Украине я его смотрю он выложил Вот
this video
это видео
that a Russian ran to surrender and exploded on
что русский бежал сдаться и взорвался на
his mini and he called this video
свое мини и он так назвал это видео
Flight of the navigator how this takes off like
Полёт навигатора как вот это взлетает
that right
так прямо
like and it turns out yeah Yeah Sorry, what is
типа и получается да Угу Извините а как
your name Andrey Andrey my name is Ivan  It's very
вас зовут Андрей Андрей меня Иван Очень
nice, well, you understand that in
приятно ну вы же понимаете то что в
any
любой
country Well, there is its own
стране Ну есть своя
Propaganda, even in the same
Пропаганда даже в той же вашей
Great Britain, you I don't know in which
Великобритании вы Я не знаю в какой
country exactly, Great Britain Yes,
именно стране Великобритании Да
I do Well, okay In short, in England If
я это ж Ну хорошо Короче в Англии Если
so, then in England, mache I just know
так то в Англии маче Просто я знаю то
that Great Britain is generally a kingdom
что Великобритания - это вообще царство
there How many countries are there, five, I think, if I'm
там Сколько стран пять по-моему если я
not mistaken Well, in short, there, if you take
не ошибаюсь Ну короче там если так брать
Scotland, that's further Yes, yes, yes, Ireland,
Шотландия это дальше Да да да Ирландия
there, and in Manchester Yes, I understand, well,
там и в Манчестере Да я понял вот и ну
everywhere there is its own Propaganda, and as if a
везде есть своя Пропаганда и как бы э
Ukrainian correspondent posted a video
украинский корреспондент выложил видео
calling it, well, Flight of the Navigator As you
назвав это ну Полёт навигатора Как вы
said, a Russian mine Well, no, there is no
сказали Российская мина Ну не нет
exception to the fact that it was a
исключения того то что это была
Ukrainian mine If this is the front line
украинская мина если это Линия фронта
from the Ukrainian side, that is, ours must
со стороны Украины то есть наши должны
storm, go, it
штурмовать идти
turns out that we are going forward, they are essentially
получается у нас мыж идём вперёд они по
[music]
[музыка]
He posted this video and wrote
он типа Выложил это видео да написал
Flight of the Navigator and in his
Полёт навигатора и у него там в чате в
Telegram chat, his subscribers were just
телеграме его подписчики они прямо
going crazy, they were laughing there that the
бесновалась они там смеялись что
Russian one was torn, in short, there, well,
разорванная у русского короче там ну
such that
такие прямо
even the Ukrainians were laughing Well, yes, his subscribers,
аж украинцы смеялись Ну да подписчики
well, and  what else can they do but
ну а что им ещё делать только
laugh Yes and why do they
смеяться Да а почему они вот так не
dislike us
любят нас
Russians so much Well, you know, in fact,
русских ну знаете у них на самом деле
even if you go into history after the
если даже вдаваться в историю после
Great Patriotic War If you know
Великой Отечественной войны Если знаете
what Western Ukraine is Well, where
что такое Западная Украина Ну там где
these bars are Well, relatively speaking, I won't
баров эти Да ну условно говоря да не
call them anything there Well, Western
буду там их никак называть Ну западные
Ukrainians In
украинцы В
general, in fact, after the Great
общем они на самом деле после Великой
Patriotic War, they really had a
Отечественной войны они ж очень
lot of machine guns, even in the fields and
много с автоматами даже по полям по
mountains, they
горам лазили
committed genocide, they even after the
устраивали геноцид они даже после
collapse of the Soviet Union, when Ukraine
распада Советского Союза когда Украина
became
стала
demilitarized, in Western Ukraine,
демилитаризованной на Западной Украине
who speak Russian That is,
которые разговаривают по-русски То есть
they didn't have such a thing, they say like they
у них не было такого вот говорят типа
banned the Russian language there in
там запретили русский язык там в
some relatively speaking year when it
каком-то условно говоря году когда
started But this is not true
началось Но это ВС неправда
I don't know this because this
Вот это не я знаю потому что вот этот
Sanya Prokhorov Well, the one from Odnoklassnik, he
Саня Прохоров Ну который Одноклассник он
was a teacher, he taught
же был преподавателем он ээ преподавал
physics at the university Yes and he
физику э в университете Да и он мне
told me even before the Maidan before the Maidan
рассказывал ещё до Майдана до Майдана
it was
это был
2000, the eleventh year, the eleventh, the
2000 одиннадцатый год одиннадцатый
twelfth year yes yes, the eleventh year,
двенадцатый год да да одиннадцатый год
Yanukovych was still in Ukraine  Yes, and
это ещё Янукович был в Украине Да и он
he went to Lviv for a conference on
он ездил на во Львов на конференцию по
physics and said that he was
физике по физике и рассказывал что его
beaten up, he was beaten up because he, like,
избили его избили за то что он типа и
spoke Russian there, the
по-русски там разговаривал преподаватели
university teachers beat up Lvivsky Well, Yak is
университета избили Львовского Ну Яка
not my classmate San about who
нет моего одноклассника Сан про который
died later, well, it’s just like I’m
погиб потом вот это ну просто я же
saying, he taught physics and went
говорю он же физику преподавал и поехал
to some kind of like their teachers,
на какой-то как у них учителей
these scientists, teachers, they have
этих учёных преподавателей у них там
some kind of conference there, yeah, so to speak,
конференции какие-то да условно говоря
some kind of Yes, and in Lviv there was
какой-то Да и во Львове проходил этот
some kind of international conference and
международный там какой-то конференция и
he was beaten up in the corridor somewhere there,
его в коридоре побили где-то там в
when he came out, they came to him Just
туалет он когда вышел его пришли Просто
like that, well, he was lying in the hospital for 3 days
так что ну он лежал в 3 дня там в
and he said in the hospital, like,
больнице и то говорит в больнице типа
how they looked at me Well, he was afraid
как на меня смотрели Так ну он боялся
that they would put something in him so that
что его что-то там ему подмешать чтобы
he would die,
он умер
like, he recovered a little, immediately got on the
типа он чуть-чуть оклемался сразу на
train and ran back through Belarus He
поезд и бегом через Белорусь назад
went, well,
Поехал да
anything can happen in reality Well, well,
ну всякое бывает на самом деле Ну вот Ну
I just know these events
я просто знаю вот эти вот ну события
that took place in Western Ukraine
которые именно на Западной Украине
Well, I can only think from this,
происходили Ну могу только из этого
otherwise,
мыслить а по-другому
they are all being forced to speak purely
то что их сейчас всех заставляют чисто
in the language now  razmot Well I can't say anything
на мове размот Ну не могу ничего сказать
very many Ukrainians also communicate
очень многие украинцы также общаются
in Russian I actually
по-русски я на самом деле у вас тоже
hear a little bit of such an accent in you too
такой акцент слышу немножко
Well G here we have look at us in Rostov Yes I
Ну Г вот есть смотри у нас в Ростове Да
don't know how it is in the south like here in
не знаю как у вас на юге типа у нас в
Rostov the Great we have a lot of
Ростове Великом у нас много кто
Gakaevs with such accents yes for
Гакаев акценты такие есть да меня
some reason I am often mistaken for like the same thing
почему-то часто за принимаю типа тоже
saying that I honestly thought that you were
говоря что я честно подумал то что вы
Ukrainian give me a bra we just have dialects
украинец подай бра у нас просто говоры
like you if you were with us there are all sorts of
вот вы если бы были у нас там всякие
Vologda Yaroslavl region Yes there are a
вологодска Ярослав области Да там очень
lot of different dialects there are a
много разных Говоров есть диалектов
lot of dialects I understand well listen Well
много я понимаю ну вот слушайте Ну
Krasnodar Krai Rostov region
Краснодарский край Ростовская область у
we have nothing similar to us in
нас ни чем-то Похоже да на нас у нас
general in our villages Well you know
вообще в деревнях Ну там знаете такие
there such remote villages or villages
глухие деревни какие-нибудь там или сёла
on Sudzhi
на суджи базарят
people speak Ukrainian right on the floor And
люди прям ну на полу украинско А ты
what year were you born I 2001 this You are 23
какого года рождения Я 2001 это Тебе 23
years old yes cool And have you ever been to
года да прикольно А ты когда-то был в
Ukraine Well I'm telling you I generally
Украине Ну я же говорю я вообще ну там
fight there Well like not as a military man And so  before
воюю Ну типа не как военный А так до
the war he came Yes when he was oh listen
войны приезжал Да когда был ой слушайте
now I remember well when I was still little
сейчас вспомню ну когда ещё маленький
right 4 years old then 8 years old I
прямо был 4 годика было потом 8 лет мне
was I went there And I
было я туда ездил И мне
was 12 years old I remember clearly well I
было 12 лет прямо отчётливо помню ну я
was Nikolaev Odessa region I Well
был Николаевская Одесская область я Ну
not to rest with my relatives there And where are they
отдыхать не у меня родные там А где они
now well I don't communicate with him and what Well
сейчас ну я с ним не общаюсь а что Ну
they wished well they say death wish so that
они желали ну смерти желают говорят чтоб
I And why did they what these Westerners also
я А почему они что эти западенцы тоже
no So wait stop And what happened to them
нет Так подожди стоп А что с ними
Well it's just that at uh at my aunt's
случилось Ну просто у у там у тёти моей
for example uh goes uh
например э ходит э
daughter to school she's 15 now she's
дочка в школу ей 15 лет сейчас
turned she goes with a school bag there
исполнилось она ходит с портфелем там
to cut and things like that Wait Stop
резать и тому подобные вещи Подожди Стоп
so your aunt wasn't a Westerner Well
так твоя ж тётка не западенка была Ну
she had a normal attitude towards Russia Yes
она ж нормально к России относилась Да
they used to be normal beautiful So what what
они раньше нормально краси Так а что что
happened What did they do to her that she
случилось Что с ней сделали что она так
started talking like that about you and Russia well here it
начала говорить про тебя и Россию ну вот
started and everything so wait the fact that
началось сво и всё так подожди то что
the aunt didn't
тётка не
appreciate you want to free him
оценила вы хотите освободить его
e Well listen for them Well we are occupiers
е Ну слушайте для них же Ну мы оккупанты
attacked all that Wait  Stop I just Well
напали все дела Подожди Стоп Я просто Ну
I have some acquaintances there from
у меня есть некоторые знакомые там из
Ukraine but I don't communicate much Yes but I
Украины но я не сильно общаюсь Да но я
understand that there are a lot of people there They are
так понимаю что там много людей Они как
just supporting Russia Yes they want
раз и поддерживают Россию Да они хотят
liberation from this Nazi regime
освобождения от этого нацистского режима
that is eating them up in Kyiv And why do they
который в Киеве заел нути А почему они
hate you then If you are a
тогда ненавидят вас Если вы
liberator some people who Well the
освободитель какие-то люди которые Ну
majority of people there really
там же большинство людей реально
hate us Russians not Well look your
ненавидят нас русских не Ну смотри твоя
aunt She is from Nikolaev or Odessa
тётя Она из Николаевской или Одесской
region Yes this is not Western Ukraine this is the
области Да это не Западная Украина это
south there are Russian
юг там русские
cities why does she hate you Well that's
города почему она ненавидит тебя Ну вот
how my own
так родного
niece I am not a relative Well not a relative Well the
племяшку я не родной Ну не родной Ну
nephew is still a relative some kind of
племянник родственник всё равно какой-то
relative Well yeah well well like
родственник Так ну да ну ну типа напали
the occupiers attacked you came here and what are you
оккупанты на вы сюда пришли а что ты
telling your
тёте говоришь
aunt nothing I am not saying That is you really it
ниче Я не говорю То есть ты реально
turns out well the aunt perceives that you
получается ну тётя воспринимает что ты
came yes let her think what she wants but what is
пришёл е да пусть что хочет думает но
the point of me communicating with her well wait one more
смысл мне с ней общаться ну подожди ещё
time Well it's your aunt anyway some kind of
раз Ну это твоя тётя всё рано какая-то
relative you went to see her you have some kind of
родня ты к ней ездил у тебя какая-то
damn
блин
some kind of feelings there must be  still
какая-то чувства должны быть всё-таки
Memories auntie you know The
Воспоминания тётя ро знаете Самое
funniest thing is that I have a cousin,
смешное то что у меня брат двоюродный у
his last name is the same as mine, his name is the same as mine, the
него фамилия как у меня его зовут Как
only thing is that his patronymic is
меня у него Единственное только отчество
different, he fought against me in the same
другое он против меня воевал на одном же
direction, only he died, and I'm
направлении только он погиб А я
alive, well, like he's my grandfather, he
живой Ну и типа он он у меня дедушка Он
was born in Ukraine, in
в Украине родился как раз-таки в
Nikolaev, and my
Николаеве и
grandmother, they then moved to Russia, and
бабушка они переехали потом в Россию и
when my grandfather ended up in the hospital with a stroke,
когда дедушка попал с инсультом в
all the relatives, except for his
больничку все родственники Кроме его
sister and her husband, who are already
родной сестры и её мужа которые уже
elderly people, who
пожилые люди ну которые за Россию
really said for Russia that, well, here and there,
реально говорили то что ну там туда-сюда
such and such, well, for Russia, in general, that is, did I
такое ну за Россию в общем то есть я
understand correctly that it turns out that
правильно понял что получается
you are your
ты своего
brother's No, I was not in it in the same
брата Нет я в него не был на одном
direction as him, yes, you were against him, well,
направлении с ним Да ты был против него
yes, that is, you are your brother's half,
Ну да то есть ты получается полти своего
well, like it turns out that way, yes, not of your own
Ну типа так получается да не по своей
free will, you went, like, you were forced, mobile phones, yes, that, well, it
воле ты пошл типа тебя заставили мобили
turns out that you, damn,
да то Ну получается что ты блин Жесть
what a horror, what a horror, well, how do you feel
какая жесть Ну а вот как Ты ощущаешь вот
that your brother died because
что твой брат погиб из-за того
you, like, went to fight in Ukraine, how do
что типа ты пошёл воевать в Украину Как
you feel about this, I
ты относишься к этому я
don't carry in  in the twelfth year he came to us he
несь в двенадцатом году приехал к нам он
lived in my
жил у меня в
house My father is his Well, my
доме Отец мой это его Ну
uncle gave him a job he
дяхан он дал ему работу он
earned money he lived with us for nothing
зарабатывал он жил у нас ни за что не
paid nothing
платил ничего не
bought with girls went to clubs
покупал с девочками гулял по клубам
went there and back and had fun In general
ходил там туда-сюда кайфовал В общем
then something ended for him
потом ему что-то там что-то у него
he went to
закончилось он поехал
Ukraine wanted to come back to us the
Укра хотел обратно к нам приехать
Maidan began and in the year he himself took a
начался Майдан и он в м году сам взял
machine gun in his hands and went to the Donetsk region
автомат в руки и пошл в донецкую область
that is to defend his country went it
то есть защищать свою страну пошёл
turns out
получается
if you can say so No well well that it
так если можете так сказать Не ну ну то
turns out that way with us Russia like
что так получается у нас Россия типа
entered Crimea and Donetsk Lugansk in what year
вошла в Крым и Донецк Луганск вчем году
they went there from the Maidan went to defend
они пошли там с Майдана пошли защищать
then
потом
Dat You can understand him because I am a
Дат Его можно понять его потому что я
citizen of the Russian Federation and
как гражданин Российской Федерации и
a subject of the kingdom Yes I have nothing
подданный королевства Да я не имею
to do with Ukraine but I understand him He
отношения к Украине но я его понимаю Он
went to defend his country on the territory of
пошл защищать свою страну на территории
his country everything is clear here with him everything
своей страны всё чётко тут с ним всё
is clear
понятно
Well you think I don’t understand that you are
Ну вы думаете я не понимаю то что вы
Ukrainian I am not
украинец я не
Ukrainian I hear how you communicate with me
украинец Я же слышу как вы со мной
how provocatively  and
как провокационно и
what is logical that Well I can also say
что логично что Ну я могу тоже сказать
that if you can look If
то что если можешь посмотреть Если
you want to check I am in the register of foreign agents
хочешь Проверить Я в реестре инагентов
in the Russian Federation I am a citizen of the
есть в Российской Федерации Я гражданин
Russian Federation you can look
Российской Федерации можешь посмотреть
popk Andrey Vasilyevich
попк Андрей Васильевич восемьдесят
born in 1981 popk Andrey
первого года рождени попк Андрей
Vasilyevich
Васильевич восемьдесят первый год
born in 1981 list of foreign agents
рождения список инагентов
by pyk Yes by
по пык Да по
pyk Vasilyevich Yes ina Agent
пык Васильевич Да ина Агент
I don't understand some not your photos
Я не пойму какие-то не ваши фотографии
so there are no photos there is it on the
так там фотографий нету это на сайте
State Duma website there or the government they
Госдумы там есть или правительство они
make lists of foreign agents look later if you don't believe Well I
делают поищешь потом если не веришь Ну я
see I can't find
смотрю не могу найти
you spiggen blocked the skeins that
вас спиген заблокированы моточки которые
were
были
blocked I can't use them
заблокированы я не могу ими пользоваться
And why were you called up on agents
А почему и на агентам вас призвали
recognized because I was leading on Twitter I was
признали потому что я вёл в Твиттере я
leading as if so to speak one can say
вёл как бы так сказать можно
anti-government yes
антиправительственные да
discrediting these Armed Forces of the
дискредитация этих Вооружённых Сил
Russian Federation I I said that since
Российской Федерации я я говорил что с
2014 yes Russia turns out to have
четырнадцатого года да Россия получается
entered Crimea Donetsk Lugansk with troops I
зашла войсками в Крым Донецк Луганск я
was not as if against yes the authorities But I kind of
не был как бы против да власти Но я типа
told it like it is and not in a pack like
рассказывал как есть и не пачкой типа у
I just have  an acquaintance he was in this FBK
меня просто знакомый был он в в этом фбк
Navalny's Anti-Corruption Foundation was
фонд борьбы с коррупцией Навального был
here uh and somewhere they pulled up that it seems
вот ээ и где-то подтянули что вроде как
like I'm connected with him and in short they added me
бы я с ним связан и короче меня добавили
to this and you are some kind of media personality
в это а вы медийная личность какая-то
or that I'm not a media person That's exactly what I'm not a
или что я не меди Вот именно что я не
media person it turns out
медийная получается
that in short I don't know how they took uh
что короче я не знаю как они брали ээ
those who were in FBK And somehow here Who was
тех кто в фбк был И как-то вот Кто
somewhere on their pages was noted
где-то у них там на страничках отмечался
or that I discussed with him
или что я с ним
So it's already clear that's
дискутировался Значит уже видно вот
how I understood
так я понял
you that is I look I
вас то есть я смотри я
don't treat you
не отношусь к тебе
with some kind of contempt Yes but I understand that
как-то с презрением Да но я понимаю что
you are mobile you are mobile Zro and the state forced you
ты мобили ты мобили Зро и тебя заставило
but I do not support the fact that
государство но я не поддерживаю то что
our state attacked Ukraine Well I
наше государство напало на Украину Ну я
understood you but I'll just Well to be honest I'll tell you
вас понял но я вам просто Ну по-честному
uh
э у
I didn't have You know what the
меня не было Знаете такого то что
Ukrainians can say as usual
ээ там как обычно украинцы могут сказать
And why didn't you go to jail and why should I
А что ты в тюрьму не сел а зачем мне в
go to jail but if the Motherland
тюрьму садиться но если меня Родина
called me Well the point is
призвала Ну смысл
I know I can't understand look Why
я знаешь что не могу понять смотри Зачем
left Kiev Because if they hadn't
ушли из-под Киева Потому что если бы не
left Kyiv the war would have ended long ago
ушли из-под Киева война бы уже давно
I have my own understanding
закончилась меня есть своё понимание
now only guys like ours have perished
сейчас только полегло пацанов типа
Well I understand I just have my own
наших Ну я понимаю у меня просто своё
opinion about this Well as
мнение насчёт этого
I
что как я
understand it maybe you
понимаю может вы тампы
know Tampa more than me but my opinion is
больше меня знаете но мо мнение в том то
that we
что нас
just like that and what didn't return back
просто так а что не вернулись назад
with troops Well we retreated to the borders
войсками Ну мы же отошли к границам прям
right right not just look instead of
правильно не просто смотри вместо того
advancing somewhere in
чтобы там продвигаться где-то на
Donbass at 5 km damn per month
Донбассе по там по 5 кмет блин в месяц
then it would be easier to throw everything at Kyiv and in
то можно проще бы на Киев кинуть все вой
short Kiev and surrendered would have been
и короче кие и сдался
enough all of Ukraine right no
было хватить всю Украину правильно нет
so the thing is that look Well as I
так дело в том что смотри Ну как я
understand it I'm not a military man but it seems to me if
понимаю я не военный но мне кажется если
Kyiv had been captured the whole country would have
бы захватили Киев всё страна бы
capitulated and would have made all the concessions
капитулировала и пошла бы на все уступки
And what do you think will happen in general well with
А вы как считаете что будет вообще ну с
Ukraine with the
Украиной со
country I think I see what we have here
страной Я думаю я вижу то что у нас тут
in Britain because I watch the news and
в Британии потому что я смотрю новости и
Russian and American and British
российские и американские и британские
ours Britain is increasing aid to Ukraine
наши Британия усиливает помощь Украине
that's how it is unofficially because
так и есть такое неофициально потому что
I
у меня
have  I'm also familiar with it, it turns out he served
есть тоже знакомый он получается служил
in the army and they were already transferred to Poland,
в армии и их перебрасывали уже в Польшу
they were in Poland for exercises, that is,
они в Польше были на учениях То есть
now they have returned, they are potentially being
сейчас они вернулись их потенциально
prepared
готовят
to introduce a contingent into the territory of
для ввода контингента на территорию
Ukraine, that's in what format I don't know, he
Украины вот В каком формате Я не знаю
doesn't tell such things, that is, well,
жну такие вещи не рассказывает он вот то
I see that the
есть ну я вижу что идёт полная
military machine, the
подготовка военной машины
propaganda machine, is being fully prepared, that is,
пропагандистской машины у нас то есть у
they are pumping up the propaganda machine, when 2 years ago the
нас накачивают уже когда 2 года назад
phrases that no, Britain will not have troops,
фразы что нет Британия не будет войска
under what conditions should we lead now, already as a
При каких условиях водить сейчас уже за
sounding opinion, they have already thrown in that there is a
зондирующего мнение уже вкид что там для
need for the presence of
спокойствия Европы нужно присутствие
European troops on the territory of Ukraine for the peace of Europe,
европейских войск на территории Украины
and so on, that is, they saw that
и так дальше то есть посмотрели что
Russia has weakened
Россия ослабла
and Well, what's the point of throwing them there to die No, for
и Ну а смысл их туда кидать погибать Нет
example, Well, as I think, I think yes They will
они например Ну как я думаю думаю да Они
take, for example, along the
возьмут встанут например по
Dnieper, Russia will not attack the
Днепру Россия же не будет атаковать
positions of British troops there in any
позиции там британских войск ни в каком
case, it's true, but Ukrainian troops will be
случае правда вот а украинские войска
transferred to other directions, for example,
перекинут на другие направления например
to Kursk, they will break through
на курски будут прорываться
there, well No, I don't have such an opinion about
там ну Нет у меня нет такого мнения по
attacking because remember when the
атаковать потому что помните когда
French troops introduced their troops
французские войска ввели свои войска
Where to Ukraine when I don't know, I saw
Куда в Украину когда я не знаю я видел
they said that perhaps they will lead there sometime
говорили что возможно там когда-то ведут
not  they weren't there were And where I didn't
не их же не было было А где я не
see Well, in what kind of grief now by You can
видел Ну в каком горе сейчас по Можно
even news Well, I wonder if I
даже новости А ну н интересно что-то
missed something in Odessa, in
пропустил в Одессе вот в
Odessa it was under Napoleon,
Одессе это при Наполеоне
no, they threw in troops exactly like, you
было нет закидывали войска именно как ну
know, like not
знаете типа не
officially, it's interesting I'll find it too now
официально интересно Я сейчас тоже найду
Well, find somewhere like mercenaries Find what kind of
Ну найди гдето как наёмников Найди какой
contingent is there, it's
там контингент аж
interesting, our intelligence calculated it
интересно вот и наша разведка вычислила
and just PU
и просто пу
them, and all the French died
их а и все французы умерли
Yes, not all Yeah, I got it And where can I read about this Well,
Да не все Ага понял А где можно об этом
find it, I'm interested, I'm like this,
почитать Ну найди мне интересно я вот
really, I
такой реально я
missed it
пропустил
now,
сейчас
French, it's even
французский это аж
[music]
[музыка]
interesting,
интересно
Ukraine now Well,
украи сечас
these were, oh no Okay, I'm lying, not Mercenaries
Ну это были а нет Ладно вру не Наёмники
And
А
these
эти
inspectors Inc. instructors, yes Well, there are plenty of instructors,
инспектора инк инструктора да А ну
and British ones, there are
инструкторов полно и британских наших
plenty of our instructors in Ukraine Yes, there are
инструкторов полно в Украине Да этих
a lot of them Because if the French were leading
куча Потому что если французы вели
a contingent, Britain would also be leading
контингент Британия тоже вела бы
a contingent We would already know Britannia
контингент Мы бы уже знали Британи
because we also kind of discussed that
потому что у нас тоже типа обсуждалось
if Booth were leading, then this would be
что вот если Бут водить то это будет
led there,
водиться там
rinia, like it's not only the British,
риния типа это не только британцы
ours And who are you  like was a stormtrooper in the
наши А ты кем типа был на
war
войне
Cool Where in what
штурмовиком Прикольно А где На каких
directions
направлениях
Avdiivka Marinka
Авдеевка Маринка
Lisichansk cool a lot of friends
Лисичанск прикольно много знакомых
died I
погибло у
won't tell you how many were there on
тебя количество не скажу были там же на
Avdiivka I saw I watch our Telegram channels
Авдеевке я вил я наши Telegram каналы
these yes there on
смотрю вот эти да то там на
Avdiivka a lot of ours
Авдеевке куча наших
died Well probably yes They
полегло Ну наверное да Там укреп типа
say there was a very
говорят был очень
strong fortification there Well I'll tell you and on Marinka there was a
сильный Ну я вам скажу и на Маринке был
strong
сильный
fortification I just Marinka Well I don't remember in
укреп Я просто Маринку Ну я не помню в
telegrams Marinka yes I remember about
телеграмах Маринку да я помню про
Avdiivka they wrote that like ADO surrendered in
авдеевку писали что типа адо сдался
blood very
кровью очень
strongly Well there were really good factories in
сильно Ну там же заводы прямо хорошие в
Avdiivka they were very
Авдеевке были они были очень
fortified Okay I'll go to bed already what did
укреплены Ладно я спать пойду уже что
your mom
тебе мамка
write to you No no Yes let's
написала Да нет Да давай нормально
communicate normally now Kato there will be no
общаемся мы сейчас Като тут будет не с
one to
кем
talk to Yes not just really After
поговорить Да не просто реально После
work tired
работы устал спать
want to sleep those What
хочу те Сколько
time is
времени
10:30 you already go to bed at 10:30 Yes I'm
10:30 ты уже ложишься спать в 10:30 Да
used to going to bed early Well sleep
рано привык спать
forever Why do
вечно Зачем
you need Glory to Ukraine come on
ве Слава Украине давай
like a
лайк
squeak  comment write on y instag I don't know
писка комент пись на й instag Я не знаю
why it's for you why you're there to
для чого це тоб для чого тоб там
watch your face and for you it's one
дивитись на оцей фейс а для тебе це один
two or three clicks Then you try me and I
два або три клика Але ти тримае мене и я
'll show you in me there's a bunch of followers and
буду казати ва в мене там Купа фолов и в
I'll be in a great mood to do New
мене буде класний настр щоб робити Нови
round video write on y instag until Andriy
кру видео пись на й instag пок Андрий
so
так
Come on I'm waiting for you
Давай я тебя чекаю